Ernst Bacon Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1898-1990 (Box 1-27)
  - Wild mustangs/Texas/Lobo girl of Devil River, Holograph draft for piano in ink; 1 p. (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Wild mustangs/Texas/Lobo girl of Devil River, Photocopy of holograph for piano; 13 p. (Box-folder 6/11)
  - The woodchuck, Holograph score for bassoon and piano; 3 p. (Box-folder 6/12)
  - The woodchuck [S.l.]: Rongwen Music, Inc., 1955., Score and part; 5 p. each; 2 copies (Box-folder 6/12)
  - The woodchuck, Photocopy of holograph for piano vocal; 3 p. (Box-folder 6/12)
  - [Woodwind pieces], Holograph scores for flute, oboe and bassoon; 19 p.; some water damage (Box-folder 6/13)
  - World take good notice, Photocopy of printed music for piano- vocal; 2 p.; unidentified publisher (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Year's end (fum, fum, fum) [S.l.]: Boosey & Hawkes, Inc., 1985., Piano-vocal score; 7 p.; 2 copies (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Yellow Sea/The banks of the Yellow Sea, Photocopy of holograph, piano-vocal score; 4 p. (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Yellow Sea/The banks of the Yellow Sea, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal; 2 p.; Published by Ernst Bacon, 1942 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Yemassee River S.C., Photocopy of holograph; 1 p.; from a spiritual slave song (Box-folder 6/17)
- Writings, 1898-1990 (Box 28-40, 53)
  Writings of Ernst Bacon arranged into two subseries: Poetry and Prose.
  Arranged by genre.
  - Poetry (Box 28-30, 53)
    Poetry, autographs, typescripts, and photocopies of unpublished original poems, and poetical writings by Ernst Bacon.
    Arranged aphabetically by title.
    - 90 degrees, n.d. (Box-folder 28/1)
    - The abstortionists, n.d. (Box-folder 28/2)
    - Academia, n.d. (Box-folder 28/3)
    - Addiction Inc., [1988] (Box-folder 28/4-6)
    - Admonition, 1988 Mar. 29 (Box-folder 28/7)
    - Advice to a young man, n.d. (Box-folder 28/8)
    - [All things in excess], 1986 May 16 (Box-folder 28/9)
    - America needs, n.d. (Box-folder 28/10)
    - And yet, n.d. (Box-folder 28/11)
    - Apothegms for artists, n.d. see also: Maxims for musicians (Box-folder 28/12)
    - The arts, n.d. (Box-folder 28/13)
    - Audiences, n.d. (Box-folder 28/14)
    - [Better to have found], 1967 (Box-folder 28/15)
    - Born every minute, n.d. (Box-folder 28/16)
    - [Days gone by], n.d. (Box-folder 28/17)
    - [Enemy of the day], 1989 July 2 (Box-folder 28/18)
    - [Fine feathers], n.d. (Box-folder 28/19)
    - Footnotes, n.d. (Box-folder 28/20)
    - General, n.d. (Box-folder 28/21)
    - Getting on, n.d. (Box-folder 28/22)
    - Hail to the native new year, n.d. (Box-folder 53b/3)
    - [If you'll only invent a new name], n.d. (Box-folder 28/23)
    - [In all my years], [1988] (Box-folder 28/24)
    - Involution, n.d. (Box-folder 28/25)
    - [It is time to act], 1988 Oct. 18 (Box-folder 28/26)
    - [I've learned all the tricks], 1988 Mar. 17 (Box-folder 28/27)
    - Das Kapital, n.d. (Box-folder 28/28)
    - [The law grows ever more lenient], n.d. (Box-folder 28/29)
    - A lesson in lunar limericks, n.d. (Box-folder 28/30)
    - Lines, n.d. see also: Verses (Box-folder 28/31-32)
    - The maestro, n.d. (Box-folder 28/33)
    - [Maxims] (Box-folder 28/34)
    - Maxims for musicians, n.d. see also: Apothegms for artists see also: Prose subseries, Maxims for musicians (Box-folder 28/35)
    - [Merest leaf], n.d. (Box-folder 28/36)
    - [Migration], n.d. (Box-folder 28/37)
    - Miscellaneous, Folders: 29/1 Drafts, [1991 July 11] 29/2 Index, n.d. 29/3 Typescript, [1991 July 11] 29/4 Undated, n.d. 29/5 Music and arts, n.d. 29/6 Musical quillets, 1966 July (Box-folder 29/1-6)
    - Nevertheless see: Hail to the native new year
    - [No light], n.d. (Box-folder 29/7-8)
    - Notebooks: Poetry, 1967-1968 see also: Prose subseries, Notebook, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 29/9)
    - Of taste, n.d. (Box-folder 29/10)
    - Orpheus' return, n.d. (Box-folder 29/11)
    - Our constitution, n.d. (Box-folder 29/12)
    - The peacock, n.d. see also: Prose subseries, Fables (Box-folder 29/13)
    - Picketing the muse, n.d. (Box-folder 29/14)
    - The political panorama, n.d. (Box-folder 29/15)
    - Politics, n.d. (Box-folder 29/16)
    - Posthumity, n.d. (Box-folder 29/17)
    - Pratt's Falls, New York, n.d. (Box-folder 29/18)
    - Science in arts, n.d. (Box-folder 29/19)
    - Serialaria, n.d. (Box-folder 29/20)
    - Shadows, n.d. (Box-folder 29/21)
    - Society, n.d. (Box-folder 29/22)
    - The super-cowpoke, n.d. (Box-folder 29/23)
    - Surfeit, 1985 May (Box-folder 29/24)
    - Symbols or abstraction, n.d. (Box-folder 29/25)
    - Taxation without molestation?, n.d. see also: Prose subseries, Taxation without molestation (Box-folder 29/26)
    - [There are captains of learning], n.d. (Box-folder 29/27)
    - They knew, n.d. (Box-folder 29/28)
    - To a distortionist, n.d. (Box-folder 29/29)
    - To a young hippie, n.d. (Box-folder 29/30)
    - [To magnify it in failure], n.d. (Box-folder 29/31)
    - To the waters (Box-folder 53a/1)
    - Tones and colors, n.d. (Box-folder 29/32)
    - Unfinished writings, n.d. (Box-folder 29/33)
    - [Utopian fantasy], n.d. (Box-folder 29/34)
    - Verses, 1984 see also: Lines (Box-folder 29/35)
    - Verses/Lines, n.d. (Box-folder 29/36)
    - The wasters, n.d. (Box-folder 30/1)
    - [When music is personal], n.d. (Box-folder 30/2)
    - [While the young man], n.d. (Box-folder 30/3)
    - Wizard oil, n.d. (Box-folder 30/4)
  - Prose (Box 30-40, 53)
    Prose, autographs, typescripts, photocopies, published and unpublished prose writings of Ernst Bacon. the subseries also contains letters to the editor.
    - 1992 (to think ahead), n.d. (Box-folder 30/5)
    - [Academia houses its own little corners], n.d. (Box-folder 30/6)
    - Academic life, n.d. (Box-folder 30/7)
    - An academic stepchild, n.d. (Box-folder 30/8)
    - [According to our president], n.d. (Box-folder 30/9)
    - Acoustical notes, n.d. (Box-folder 30/10)
    - Admonitions before a concert, 1978 May 10 (Box-folder 30/11)
    - Advice to candidates, n.d. (Box-folder 30/12)
    - Advice on teaching, n.d. (Box-folder 30/13)
    - Advice to movie and TV directors, n.d. (Box-folder 30/14)
    - Advice to music patrons, n.d. see also: Ear (Box-folder 30/15)
    - Advice to patrons, 1980 Feb.-Mar. (Box-folder 30/16)
    - Advice to politicians, n.d. (Box-folder 30/17)
    - Amateur notes on a few national heroes, n.d. (Box-folder 30/18)
    - [Amphorisms], n.d. (Box-folder 30/19)
    - [Anonymous chorus], n.d. (Box-folder 30/20)
    - Apartheid, n.d. (Box-folder 30/21)
    - Apologues, n.d. see also: Fables see also: Satires (Box-folder 30/22-25)
    - Articles, n.d. (Box-folder 31/1)
    - Articles of protest, n.d. (Box-folder 31/2)
    - The artist and the critic, 1978 apr. 14, 1984 (Box-folder 31/3)
    - As for TV, n.d. (Box-folder 31/4)
    - [As much to-do over a sprinter lopping], [1987] (Box-folder 31/5)
    - Atlantis continued, n.d. (Box-folder 31/6)
    - The avant-garde, n.d. (Box-folder 31/7)
    - [Beyond doubt, we Americans], [1987] (Box-folder 31/8)
    - The bitter price or I don't like it, n.d. (Box-folder 31/9)
    - Boldness, n.d. (Box-folder 31/10)
    - [The Boston Symphony], n.d. (Box-folder 31/11)
    - The bush, n.d. (Box-folder 31/12)
    - Carmel Festival President, n.d. (Box-folder 31/13)
    - Cement flood, n.d. (Box-folder 31/14)
    - The chapel, 1988 (Box-folder 31/15)
    - Classical vs. contempory music, n.d. (Box-folder 31/16)
    - Commonplaces, n.d. (Box-folder 31/17)
    - Common sense in music, n.d. (Box-folder 31/18)
    - Constitutional changes, n.d. (Box-folder 31/19)
    - Contests, n.d. (Box-folder 31/20)
    - [Contests in the arts], n.d. (Box-folder 31/21)
    - [Controversial letters], 1940-1979, n.d. see also: Letters to the editor, Folders: 31/22 1940s, 1950s 31/23 1960s 31/24 1970s, n.d. (Box-folder 31/22-24)
    - The crime, n.d. (Box-folder 31/25)
    - Crime and punishment, n.d. (Box-folder 31/26)
    - Crossing the Andes, n.d. (Box-folder 31/27)
    - [Defense by retaliation], n.d. (Box-folder 31/28)
    - Democratic music, n.d. (Box-folder 31/29)
    - Departure, n.d. (Box-folder 31/30)
    - Desert see: [General Comments]
    - [Despite numerous cadenzas], n.d. (Box-folder 31/31)
    - Didactic banalities, n.d. (Box-folder 31/32)
    - The dilemna of music see: Articles
    - [Dind], n.d. (Box-folder 31/33)
    - The directors of televents, n.d. (Box-folder 31/34)
    - The doctoral complot, n.d. see also: Words on music (Box-folder 31/35)
    - Doing nothing, n.d. (Box-folder 31/36)
    - Ear, 1975 Apr.-Jun. see also: Advice to music patrons see also: The symphony as a civic institution (Box-folder 53a/2)
    - Education, n.d. (Box-folder 31/37)
    - Education?, n.d. (Box-folder 31/38)
    - Ernest Bloch, 1971 Aug. (Box-folder 31/39)
    - Essays, n.d. (Box-folder 31/40-41)
    - Essays, [political], n.d. (Box-folder 32/1-2)
    - An estimate 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 32/3)
    - The ethics of music, n.d. (Box-folder 32/4)
    - The exotic garden, n.d. (Box-folder 32/5)
    - [Fables], n.d. see also: Satires see also: Apologues, Folders: 32/7 A-M, n.d. 32/8 P-U, n.d. 32/9 Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box-folder 32/6-9)
    - Farmer's Museum fascinating place see: Words on music
    - Father and son, n.d. (Box-folder 32/10)
    - Fifth amendment, n.d. (Box-folder 32/11)
    - First attempt, n.d. (Box-folder 32/12)
    - The flight of the American musician, n.d. (Box-folder 32/13)
    - Folk song, n.d. (Box-folder 32/14)
    - [Formerly the best doctors], n.d. (Box-folder 32/15)
    - Four brothers, n.d. (Box-folder 32/16)
    - From the listener, n.d. (Box-folder 32/17)
    - [General comments], n.d. (Box-folder 32/18)
    - Government and the arts, n.d. (Box-folder 32/19)
    - [A great musical iniquity], [c.1940] (Box-folder 32/20)
    - [Greatness?], n.d. (Box-folder 32/21)
    - Has the native opera a future?, 1944 Feb. 20 (Box-folder 32/22)
    - Der Herr Diktator, n.d. see also: Words on music (Box-folder 32/23)
    - History stories, 1907 Apr. 22-Jun. 4 (Box-folder 53b/6)
    - The honor of music, n.d. see also: Revolt and change (Box-folder 32/24)
    - [The Honorable Governors and Patrons of the San Francisco Orchestra], 1982 May 28 (Box-folder 32/25)
    - An honorable science, 1988 Apr. 4 (Box-folder 32/26)
    - L'hopital musicale, n.d. (Box-folder 33/1)
    - How a major career?, n.d. (Box-folder 33/2)
    - How good is TV?, n.d. (Box-folder 33/3)
    - [How long must a composer be dead], n.d. (Box-folder 33/4)
    - How much music, 1988 Apr. 20 (Box-folder 33/5)
    - How to remain a second-rate city in music, n.d. (Box-folder 33/6)
    - I disagree, n.d. (Box-folder 33/7)
    - I don't like it, n.d. see: The bitter price or I don't like it
    - [I have long been of the opinion], n.d. (Box-folder 33/8)
    - Imaginary dialogues, 1989 May 1, 1989 Aug. 31, 1989 Sept. 4, 1989 Oct. 2, [1990], n.d., Folders: 33/9 Bismark and Wilson, n.d. 33/10 Franklin and Rush, n.d. 33/11 Hamilton and Madison, 1989 May 1 33/12 Lenin and Russell, n.d. 33/13 Lincoln and Lee, 1989 Aug. 31 33/14 President of the West and King of the East, [1990] 33/15 Trotsky and Stalin, n.d. 33/16 Twain in hell, n.d. 33/17 Wilson and Mencken, 1989 Sept. 4 33/18 Complete, 1989, Oct. 2 33/19 Complete, n.d. 33/20 Incomplete, n.d. (Box-folder 33/9-20)
    - Immigration should be restricted, n.d. (Box-folder 33/21)
    - International courtesy or Manners between nations, 1958 Jan. 15 (Box-folder 34/1)
    - The interpretative art, n.d (Box-folder 34/2)
    - The interpreter, n.d. (Box-folder 34/3)
    - Introduction, n.d. (Box-folder 34/4)
    - Invention and discovery, n.d. (Box-folder 34/5)
    - Is art a mirror?, n.d. (Box-folder 34/6)
    - [It is not necessary to whitewash], n.d. (Box-folder 34/7)
    - [It seems to be], n.d. (Box-folder 34/8)
    - [I've talked enough about music], [c.1940] (Box-folder 34/9)
    - Jazz and the like, n.d. (Box-folder 34/10)
    - Jerusalem revisted, n.d. (Box-folder 34/11)
    - Keeping the wheels turning, n.d. (Box-folder 34/12)
    - The latter-day puritanism, 1965 (Box-folder 34/13)
    - A layman's view, n.d. (Box-folder 34/14)
    - Leonardo's dream, n.d. (Box-folder 34/15)
    - The lesson from England, n.d. (Box-folder 34/16)
    - The letter, n.d. (Box-folder 34/17)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1947-1999, undated see also: [Controversial letters], Folders: 34/18 1947-79 34/19 1983 Aug. 9 34/20 1987 34/21 1988-89 34/22-24 1980s 34/25 1990s 35/1-4, 53a/3 Undated (Box-folder 34/18-25, Box-folder 35/1-4, Box-folder 53a/3)
    - Life and freedom, n.d. (Box-folder 35/5)
    - [Like any merchant], n.d. (Box-folder 35/6)
    - The listener, n.d. (Box-folder 35/7)
    - Lloyd's, [1988] (Box-folder 35/8)
    - Local, n.d. (Box-folder 35/9)
    - Local and music of our day, n.d. (Box-folder 35/10)
    - A look at music see: Ear
    - A look at TV, n.d. (Box-folder 35/11)
    - Looking back, n.d. (Box-folder 35/12)
    - Lorenzo the Magnificent, n.d. (Box-folder 35/13)
    - The man from nowhere, n.d. (Box-folder 35/14)
    - Man on foot, n.d. (Box-folder 35/15)
    - Master and pupil, n.d. (Box-folder 35/16)
    - Maxims for musicians, n.d. see also: Poetry subseries, Maxims for Musicians (Box-folder 35/17)
    - Means and extremes, 1937 Apr. (Box-folder 35/18)
    - Men of genius, n.d. (Box-folder 35/19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940, 1990, undated, Folders: 35/20 [c.1940] 35/21 1990 36/1-3 Undated (Box-folder 35/20-21, Box-folder 36/1-3)
    - The mocking-bird and the crow, n.d. (Box-folder 36/4)
    - Mr. President and Faculty of Converse College, n.d. (Box-folder 36/5)
    - Music and business, n.d. (Box-folder 36/6)
    - Music and democracy, 1966 (Box-folder 36/7)
    - Music and the arts, n.d. (Box-folder 36/8)
    - Music and the piano - general, n.d. (Box-folder 36/9)
    - Music, from The Argonaut, 1934 Jan. 26-1935 Apr. 5 (Box-folder 53b/5)
    - Music in the home, n.d. (Box-folder 36/10)
    - The music teacher, n.d. (Box-folder 36/11)
    - The musical dilemme, n.d. (Box-folder 36/12)
    - Musical episodes, n.d. (Box-folder 36/13)
    - Musical notes (mostly), n.d. (Box-folder 36/14)
    - [My music ought to speak for itself], n.d. (Box-folder 36/15)
    - Native soil, 1987 winter -1988 spring (Box-folder 36/16, Box-folder 53a/4)
    - The nature of crime, n.d. (Box-folder 53b/4)
    - Neighbors, n.d. (Box-folder 36/17)
    - A new policy for symphony orchestras, n.d. (Box-folder 36/18)
    - Notebook, 1911 June 29-30 (Box-folder 36/19)
    - Notebook, 1911 Sept. 5 (Box-folder 36/20)
    - Notebook, 1911 Sept. 19 (Box-folder 36/21)
    - Notebook, 1911 (Box-folder 36/22)
    - Notebook, 1912 June 27 (Box-folder 36/23)
    - Notebook, 1912 July 24 (Box-folder 37/1)
    - Notebook, 1912 Aug. 6 (Box-folder 37/2)
    - Notebook, [c.1917] (Box-folder 37/3)
    - Notebook, 1928-31 (Box-folder 37/4)
    - Notebook, 1929 June - Dec. (Box-folder 37/5)
    - Notebook, 1938 (Box-folder 37/6-7)
    - Notebook, 1939 (Box-folder 37/8)
    - Notebook, 1944 (Box-folder 37/9)
    - Notebook, 1940-45 see: Notebook, 1950
    - Notebook, 1946-48 (Box-folder 37/10)
    - Notebook, 1940s see also: Notebook, 1950 (Box-folder 37/11)
    - Notebook, 1950 (Box-folder 37/12)
    - Notebook, 1951, 1953 (Box-folder 37/13)
    - Notebook, 1956, 1958-60 (Box-folder 37/14)
    - Notebook, 1960 see also: Notebook, 1950 (Box-folder 37/15-16)
    - Notebook, 1960-61 (Box-folder 37/17)
    - Notebook, 1961-62 (Box-folder 37/18)
    - Notebook, 1963-64 (Box-folder 37/19)
    - Notebook, 1967 (Box-folder 37/20)
    - Notebook, 1967-68 (Box-folder 37/21)
    - Notebook, 1968 (Box-folder 37/22-23)
    - Notebook, 1970 (Box-folder 37/24)
    - Notebook, 1971 (Box-folder 38/1)
    - Notebook, [c. 1980] (Box-folder 38/2)
    - Notebook, 1980-83 (Box-folder 38/3)
    - Notebook, 1981-85 (Box-folder 38/4)
    - Notebook, 1982-85 (Box-folder 38/5)
    - Notebook, 1990 Jan (Box-folder 38/6)
    - Notebook, undated (Box-folder 38/7-13, Box-folder 39/1-3)
    - Notes on the presidency, n.d. (Box-folder 39/3)
    - A novel, n.d. (Box-folder 39/4)
    - [Now the "contras" are about to invade Nicaragua], n.d. (Box-folder 39/5)
    - Of careers, n.d. (Box-folder 39/6)
    - Of musical study, [1941 Oct. 19] see also: On music (Box-folder 39/7)
    - Of tyranny, n.d. (Box-folder 39/8)
    - On Ansel Adams, 1989 Apr. 28 (Box-folder 39/9)
    - On art, n.d. (Box-folder 39/10)
    - On composition and its theory, n.d. (Box-folder 39/11)
    - On myself, n.d. (Box-folder 39/12)
    - On music, n.d. (Box-folder 39/13)
    - On music in America... today..., 1966 Feb.-Mar. (Box-folder 39/14)
    - On musical study see: Of musical study
    - On painting, n.d. (Box-folder 39/15)
    - On teaching, n.d. (Box-folder 39/16)
    - One hundred scores, n.d. (Box-folder 39/17)
    - [One need be no environmentalist], [c.1968] (Box-folder 39/18)
    - [One of my notable traits], n.d. (Box-folder 39/19)
    - An open letter to the President [of the United States], n.d. (Box-folder 39/20)
    - The operation, n.d. (Box-folder 39/21)
    - The orchestra, n.d. (Box-folder 39/22)
    - [Our musical idiom], n.d. (Box-folder 39/23)
    - Our taxes where?, n.d. (Box-folder 39/24)
    - The parlour song book, n.d. (Box-folder 39/25)
    - Patience, n.d. (Box-folder 39/26)
    - Patronage, n.d. (Box-folder 39/27)
    - "Pedagogy" so called, n.d. (Box-folder 39/28)
    - The penny discount, n.d. (Box-folder 39/29)
    - [Perhaps the greatest achievements in art], n.d. (Box-folder 39/30)
    - Pianists then and now, 1981 Nov. (Box-folder 39/31)
    - Picture of a conductor, n.d. (Box-folder 39/32)
    - Pitapatation, n.d. (Box-folder 39/33)
    - Poetry in search of music, 1941 (Box-folder 39/34)
    - The poet's odyssey, n.d. see also: Fables (Box-folder 39/35)
    - The portrait, n.d. (Box-folder 39/36)
    - [Precepts], n.d. (Box-folder 39/37)
    - Prelude to an address on piano and melody, 1967 May 11 (Box-folder 39/38)
    - The presidency of the nation, n.d. (Box-folder 39/39)
    - The private estate see: Words on music
    - Problems and motives, n.d. (Box-folder 39/40)
    - Radio address by Ernst Bacon, 1941 Oct. 27 (Box-folder 40/1)
    - [Reforms never come about through reason], n.d. (Box-folder 40/2)
    - Re-incarnation, n.d. (Box-folder 40/3)
    - [The resignation], n.d. (Box-folder 40/4)
    - Retirement by the calender, n.d. (Box-folder 40/5)
    - Retirement by the clock, n.d. (Box-folder 40/6)
    - The return, n.d. (Box-folder 40/7)
    - Revolt and change, n.d. see also: The honor of music (Box-folder 40/8)
    - Satires, n.d. see also: Apologues see also: Fables (Box-folder 40/9)
    - The servant, n.d. (Box-folder 40/10)
    - Servant and master, n.d. (Box-folder 40/11)
    - Smithsonian Institute, n.d. (Box-folder 40/12)
    - Song, 1988 Apr. 14 (Box-folder 40/13)
    - The statement, n.d. (Box-folder 40/14)
    - Stories, n.d. (Box-folder 40/15)
    - Story of a soldier who died in WWI, n.d. (Box-folder 40/16)
    - The symphony, n.d. (Box-folder 40/17)
    - The symphony as a civic institution, n.d. see also: Ear (Box-folder 40/18)
    - A talk on regional music, n.d. (Box-folder 40/19)
    - Taxation without molestation?, n.d. see also: Poetry subseries, Taxation without molestation (Box-folder 40/20)
    - The teacher as artist, 1966 Apr. 21 (Box-folder 40/21)
    - [That boasted new "verismo"], n.d. (Box-folder 40/22)
    - [There is no worse pollution today], n.d. (Box-folder 40/23)
    - Thoughts of a vagrant, n.d. (Box-folder 40/24)
    - Three brothers, n.d. (Box-folder 40/25)
    - The toucan, n.d. see also: Fables (Box-folder 40/26)
    - [To sermonize about human rights and democracy], [1987] (Box-folder 40/27)
    - Too much music?, n.d. (Box-folder 40/28)
    - Toward a musical home-rule, n.d. (Box-folder 40/29)
    - Toward our third century, n.d. (Box-folder 40/30)
    - The tragedy of American music, [c.1940] (Box-folder 40/31)
    - The trials of failing eyesight, n.d. (Box-folder 40/32)
    - Tribute in reverse, n.d. (Box-folder 40/33)
    - [True West], 1988 Apr. 7 (Box-folder 40/34)
    - Truth and untruth, n.d. (Box-folder 40/35)
    - Union, n.d. (Box-folder 40/36)
    - [A university dean], n.d. (Box-folder 40/37)
    - Utilitarian monopoly, 1988 Apr. 17 (Box-folder 40/38)
    - The value of choral music, n.d. (Box-folder 40/39)
    - Vienna, n.d. (Box-folder 40/40)
    - Viewing the mainstream, n.d. (Box-folder 40/41)
    - Waste, n.d. (Box-folder 40/42)
    - The whale aimed the shark, n.d. (Box-folder 40/43)
    - What about TV?, n.d. (Box-folder 40/44)
    - [What is democracy?], n.d. (Box-folder 40/45)
    - [What is this high standard of living], n.d. (Box-folder 40/46)
    - [What is TV news these days?], [1987] (Box-folder 40/47)
    - [Whatever the virtues of our jury system], n.d (Box-folder 40/48)
    - [The White House has become], n.d. (Box-folder 40/49)
    - Why I am not avant-garde, n.d. (Box-folder 40/50)
    - [Wife-abuse is a common subject], n.d. (Box-folder 40/51)
    - Women in music, n.d. (Box-folder 40/52)
    - A word to TV, radio and movie producers, n.d. (Box-folder 40/53)
    - Yesterday and today, n.d. (Box-folder 40/54)
    - Words on music, 1965 see also: Doctoral complot (Box-folder 40/55, Box-folder 53a/5)
- Correspondence, 1898-1990 (Box 41-51)
  Correspondence sent and received by Ernst Bacon. This series is arranged into two suberies: Family Correspondence and General Correspondence.
  Arrangement is by subject.
  - Family Correspondence (Box 41-42)
    Family correspondence, letters from and to Ernst Bacon from his blood relatives, father, mother, siblings, his own immediate family, wives, and European relatives, with and unidentified family folder.
    Arranged aphabetically by correspondent.
    - Atkins, Clara P., n.d. (Box-folder 41/1)
    - Bacon, Alphons, 1916, 1944-48, n.d. (Box-folder 41/2)
    - Bacon, Analee Camp, 1939-78, n.d. see also: Bacon, Paul (Box-folder 41/3)
    - Bacon, Arthur, 1957, 1962 (Box-folder 41/4)
    - Bacon, Charles S. Sr., 1923-46, n.d. (Box-folder 41/5)
    - Bacon, Charles S. Jr., 1936-49 (Box-folder 41/6)
    - Bacon, David, 1988, 1990, n.d. (Box-folder 41/7)
    - Bacon, Ellen, 1964-91, n.d., Letters to: 1929-81, n.d. (Box-folder 41/8-14)
    - Bacon, Hilary, 1961, 1967 (Box-folder 42/1)
    - Bacon, Madi, 1938-39, 1955-62 (Box-folder 42/2)
    - Bacon, Marga, 1943-85, n.d. (Box-folder 42/3)
    - Bacon, Paul, 1949, 1952, 1961-69, concerning his estate: 1961-69 (Box-folder 42/4)
    - Bacon, Peggy, 1948-51, Letters to: 1947-66, n.d. (Box-folder 42/5-11)
    - Bacon, Penty, 1936, n.d. (Box-folder 42/12)
    - Camp, Wilbur, 1939, 1943 (Box-folder 42/13)
    - [Farrell], Guy, n.d. and Neil [Farrell] (Box-folder 42/14)
    - Farrell, Quintus William, 1988, n.d. (Box-folder 42/15)
    - Gammon, Eleanor, 1912-15, n.d. (Box-folder 42/16)
    - Gammon, Stella, n.d. (Box-folder 42/17)
    - Gammon, Vera, 1913 (Box-folder 42/18)
    - [LeHalk?], Lili, 1986 (Box-folder 42/19)
    - Lillie, Frances C., 1936, 1938 (Box-folder 42/20)
    - Lillie, Frank Rattray, 1934, 1938 (Box-folder 42/21)
    - Lillie, Ralph S., 1928, 1939, 1941 (Box-folder 42/22)
    - Pichler, Hans, 1963 (Box-folder 42/23)
    - Pinscoff, Karl, 1972; Susi Pinscoff, and Thomas Pinscoff (Box-folder 42/24)
    - Rosthorn, Arthur von, 1926-33 (Box-folder 42/25)
    - Rosthorn, Marid von, 1923-50, 1966, n.d. (Box-folder 42/26)
    - Trauner, Richard, 1947, 1954, 1961-82 (Box-folder 42/27)
    - Unidentified, 1912-36, n.d. (Box-folder 42/28)
    - Welch, Robert, 1929 (Box-folder 42/29)
    - Wendt, Louise, 1969 (Box-folder 42/30)
    - Wendt, [?], 1972, 1986 (Box-folder 42/31)
    - Wheeler, Emily Lillie, 1927, n.d. (Box-folder 42/32)
  - General Correspondence (Box 43-51)